<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-05-08T22:43:10-07:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Grey, Blu and Ash</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Keep the bugs out this summer! Chemical-Free!</title><link href="/2023/06/13/keep-the-bugs-out.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keep the bugs out this summer! Chemical-Free!" /><published>2023-06-13T12:19:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-06-13T12:19:00-07:00</updated><id>/2023/06/13/keep-the-bugs-out</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/06/13/keep-the-bugs-out.html"><![CDATA[<p>As the temperature rises and the sun shines brighter, summer brings with it a delightful array of activities and outdoor adventures. However, along with the joys of summer come the inevitable presence of bugs. From buzzing mosquitoes to pesky flies, these unwelcome visitors can quickly turn a relaxing evening on the porch into an annoying ordeal. But fear not! In this blog post, we will explore a simple yet effective solution to keep bugs at bay during the summer months: using a fan. Let’s dive in and discover how embracing the breeze can be your secret weapon against these winged intruders.</p>

<ol>
  <li>How Bugs Are Deterred by Fans</li>
</ol>

<p>Believe it or not, bugs are not particularly fond of strong air currents. When it comes to flying insects, such as mosquitoes and flies, their light bodies make them susceptible to even gentle winds. By strategically placing a fan or two, you create a barrier of airflow that disrupts their flight patterns and makes it difficult for them to navigate effectively. Furthermore, the constant airflow generated by the fan also disperses the carbon dioxide and body heat we emit, which are two primary attractants for bugs.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Choose the Right Fan</li>
</ol>

<p>When selecting a fan for bug control, consider the following factors:</p>

<p>a. Size and Power: Opt for a fan with sufficient size and power to create a steady breeze across your desired area. A larger fan with adjustable speed settings allows you to customize the airflow according to your needs.</p>

<p>b. Oscillation Feature: Fans with an oscillation feature are ideal, as they can cover a broader area and distribute airflow more evenly. This helps ensure bugs are deterred from all corners of your outdoor space.</p>

<p>c. Outdoor Durability: Ensure that the fan you choose is designed for outdoor use, with weather-resistant construction and materials. This will ensure its longevity and performance even in humid or rainy conditions.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Placement Matters</li>
</ol>

<p>Strategic placement of the fan is crucial for optimal bug deterrence. Here are some tips to keep in mind:</p>

<p>a. Entry Points: Position the fan near entry points such as doors, windows, or outdoor dining areas to create a barrier that prevents bugs from entering. Point the fan outward to blow bugs away from your space.</p>

<p>b. Seating Areas: If you have a patio or seating area, place the fan close to where people gather. This will not only create a pleasant breeze but also help keep bugs at a distance.</p>

<p>c. Consider Multiple Fans: Depending on the size of your outdoor space, consider using multiple fans strategically placed to cover different areas effectively. This ensures comprehensive bug control across the entire area.</p>

<p>We decided to solve this problem by strategically placing a fan by our patio door and use home automation toggle on and off when the door opens and closes.</p>

<p>What we used to achieve this:</p>

<ol>
  <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B086MFKGJ8/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=greybluash-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=dd0813c7b231bdd97dffc823a36fd165&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325">Oscillating Tower Fan</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0753CDY86/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=greybluash-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=e4888e531d1492767c9d7df360a9e77a&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325">BroadLink</a> IR and RF Universal Remote</li>
  <li>Some type of smart door sensor (we leveraged our existing <a href="https://www.amazon.com/stores/page/8B5A2A32-E2E6-4FAC-B34E-26D2762AAF43/?_encoding=UTF8&amp;store_ref=SB_A00396583DFFFNJRGMA6V&amp;pd_rd_plhdr=t&amp;aaxitk=87f79204579d5a083679b4bbeb2a034d&amp;hsa_cr_id=0&amp;lp_asins=B0BYTJNKZ5%252CB0BYTL3WFM&amp;lp_query=abode%2520security&amp;lp_slot=auto-sparkle-hsa-tetris&amp;ref_=sbx_be_s_sparkle_lsi4d_cta&amp;pd_rd_w=KQqQt&amp;content-id=amzn1.sym.cd95889f-432f-43a7-8ec8-833616493f4a%253Aamzn1.sym.cd95889f-432f-43a7-8ec8-833616493f4a&amp;pf_rd_p=cd95889f-432f-43a7-8ec8-833616493f4a&amp;pf_rd_r=M8J7EVVMGRRYM7CZP3M4&amp;pd_rd_wg=CJRVP&amp;pd_rd_r=3703fb3a-ac73-4a49-865f-b44a2dd5234e&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=greybluash-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=a81ca6fc38f088438e3c5dd273774b27&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325">Abode Security System</a> door sensor)</li>
  <li>Home Assistant automation</li>
</ol>

<p>Once we have strategically placed the fan by the patio door we positioned the BroadLink across from it in a concealed manner to transmit signals to toggle the fan on and off.</p>

<p>If this is your first time setting up BroadLink, you will need to learn the commands from the remote that came with the fan to be able to control it through Home Assistant. Here is a link to their <a href="https://www.home-assistant.io/integrations/broadlink/">documentation</a>.</p>

<p><strong>2023-06-16</strong> Update: Using the BroadLink to transmit IR signals to toggle on and off the tower fan did not work consistently. Largely due to the positioning of the BroadLink and the the communications require line of sight. Meaning if someone happened to be standing in front of the fan at the point the patio door was open, the fan would not receive the command.</p>

<p>Due to the limitations of IR, I decided to use <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07B7NXV4R/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;tag=greybluash-20&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;linkId=09e5aeb7c2dd1aaa81e51c1d094eff6f&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325">Switchbot</a> smart button pusher instead. This solution turned out to be way more reliable.</p>

<p>Once you have learned the commands, now it is time to program the automation, below is an example of mine that I used.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/Screenshot-2023-06-13-at-4.15.16-PM-429x1024.png" alt="homeassistant keep the bugs out" /></p>

<p>And that is it!</p>

<p>This summer, don’t let pesky bugs dampen your outdoor enjoyment. Harness the power of airflow and keep them at bay with the help of a fan. By strategically positioning fans, you create a protective barrier that disrupts their flight patterns</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the temperature rises and the sun shines brighter, summer brings with it a delightful array of activities and outdoor adventures. However, along with the joys of summer come the inevitable presence of bugs. From buzzing mosquitoes to pesky flies, these unwelcome visitors can quickly turn a relaxing evening on the porch into an annoying ordeal. But fear not! In this blog post, we will explore a simple yet effective solution to keep bugs at bay during the summer months: using a fan. Let’s dive in and discover how embracing the breeze can be your secret weapon against these winged intruders.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DIY Electric Fireplace for Your Home</title><link href="/2023/05/26/diy-electric-fireplace.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DIY Electric Fireplace for Your Home" /><published>2023-05-26T19:06:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-05-26T19:06:00-07:00</updated><id>/2023/05/26/diy-electric-fireplace</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/05/26/diy-electric-fireplace.html"><![CDATA[<p>A fireplace instantly adds warmth, comfort, and ambiance to any room. However, traditional wood-burning fireplaces can be costly and require regular maintenance. Thankfully, there’s an alternative solution that allows you to enjoy the cozy atmosphere of a fireplace without the hassle: a DIY electric insert fireplace. In this blog post, we’ll explore the benefits of electric fireplaces and provide a step-by-step guide to help you create your very own electric insert fireplace.</p>

<p>Benefits of Electric Insert Fireplaces:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Easy Installation: Electric insert fireplaces are incredibly simple to install compared to traditional fireplaces. You don’t need to worry about venting or chimneys, making them suitable for both apartments and houses.</li>
  <li>Cost-effective: Electric fireplaces are energy-efficient, allowing you to enjoy the warmth without significantly increasing your energy bill. They also eliminate the need for purchasing and storing firewood, saving you money in the long run.</li>
  <li>Low Maintenance: Say goodbye to cleaning up ashes, soot, and chimney inspections. Electric insert fireplaces require minimal maintenance, with no need for regular cleanups or chimney sweeps.</li>
  <li>Safe and Eco-friendly: Electric fireplaces eliminate the risks associated with open flames, such as accidental fires or harmful fumes. They also provide a greener option, as they don’t release any pollutants or carbon emissions into the environment.</li>
</ol>

<p>Creating Your DIY Electric Insert Fireplace: Before you start the installation process, here’s a list of materials you’ll need:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Electric fireplace insert: Choose a model that fits your desired size and style. Ensure it comes with a remote control and adjustable heat settings. We decided on this model that fit our current traditional fireplace on Amazon.</li>
  <li>Fireplace surround: You can construct a custom mantel and surround using materials like wood, brick, or stone. However if you already have a traditional fireplace you can create an insert out of 2x4 that will hold the electric insert in place.</li>
  <li>Tools: Measuring tape, screws, screwdriver, level, drill, and a jigsaw (if necessary).</li>
  <li>Electrical tools: Wire strippers, electrical tape, and wire connectors. (if necessary).</li>
  <li>Safety equipment: Gloves, safety goggles, and a fire extinguisher.</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="/assets/firepalce/IMG_4383-768x1024.jpeg" alt="Fireplace Before" /></p>

<p>Step-by-step Installation Guide:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Measure and prepare: Measure the dimensions of your fireplace opening to ensure a proper fit. Clear the area and remove any debris or obstacles.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Assemble the surround: Construct your fireplace surround according to your preferred design. If using wood, measure and cut the pieces to size. Secure the surround to the wall using screws and a level to ensure it’s straight.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Prepare the electrical connections: Locate an electrical outlet nearby or hire a licensed electrician to install one. Ensure the outlet is properly grounded and can handle the electrical load of the fireplace.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Install the electric insert: Carefully follow the manufacturer’s instructions to install the electric fireplace insert within the opening of the surround. Use the provided mounting brackets or screws to secure it in place. We went the easy route since we had an outlet close by and purchased a flat extension cable that will split in through the side and go inside the fireplace behind the insert.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Connect the wiring: Turn off the power supply to the area. Connect the fireplace’s wiring to the electrical outlet using wire connectors, ensuring the connections are tight and secure. Use wire strippers to expose the necessary lengths of wire and cover the connections with electrical tape. Since we did not have to do any extra wiring but we were very interested in the power consumption we purchased a couple smart plugs that has power monitoring capability.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Test and finalize: Double-check all connections and ensure everything is securely fastened. Turn on the power supply and test the fireplace’s functions, including the heat, flame, and lighting settings. Adjust the settings according to your preferences.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p><img src="/assets/firepalce/IMG_4380-1024x768.jpeg" alt="Building the frame" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/firepalce/IMG_4381-1024x768.jpeg" alt="Painting the frame" /></p>

<p>With a DIY electric insert fireplace, you can transform any space into a cozy retreat without the hassle and maintenance of traditional fireplaces. Enjoy the warmth and ambiance with the added benefits of cost-effectiveness, ease of installation, and environmental friendliness. Follow our step-by-step guide to create your own electric insert fireplace and elevate your home’s atmosphere. Stay warm and cozy all year round!
<img src="/assets/firepalce/IMG_4403-768x1024.jpeg" alt="After" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A fireplace instantly adds warmth, comfort, and ambiance to any room. However, traditional wood-burning fireplaces can be costly and require regular maintenance. Thankfully, there’s an alternative solution that allows you to enjoy the cozy atmosphere of a fireplace without the hassle: a DIY electric insert fireplace. In this blog post, we’ll explore the benefits of electric fireplaces and provide a step-by-step guide to help you create your very own electric insert fireplace.]]></summary></entry></feed>